The best thing you can say to a victim
of child sexual abuse or of sexual
assault is, "I believe you." That's by
far the best thing that you can say. The
worst thing you can say is, "I don't
believe you." And so the Department of
Justice and the FBI are saying that they
don't believe hundreds of girls. And
that's that's that's important to me.
Hi, I'm John Kuryaku and welcome back to
Deep Focus.
The Jeffrey Epstein story is the biggest
story in the country right now. And it's
kind of crazy because it's about 20
years old, but it seems like every day
that goes by, we hear a new revelation.
And now the one person convicted and
jailed for sex crimes against children
in this case, the pimp essentially,
Galileain Maxwell,
is looking at the idea of a presidential
pardon. This thing is complicated. It's
more complicated than we realize. There
are very clear-cut good guys and bad
guys. And we are going to talk with the
country's leading expert. I don't say
those words lightly. the country's
leading expert on the Jeffrey Epstein
case. That's Nick Bryant. He is a
prominent journalist and author. He is
the author of a whole bunch of acclaimed
books, including The Franklin Scandal, A
Story of Power Brokers, Child Abuse and
Betrayal, and his latest book, The Truth
About Watergate: A Tale of Extraordinary
Lies and Liars. and he's particularly
well known as the leading expert on this
case who actually owned and released the
Epstein blackbook. Nick, thank you so
much for being with us. This is really
exciting for me.
>> Great to be with you, John.
>> Thank you. And there's so much to ask
you. I'm not even sure where to begin.
So, I guess the the most logical place
is to start at the beginning. You wrote
in the Sheer Post back in 2021 that
Jeffrey Epstein had been known to the
FBI as a likely pedophile all the way
back in 1995.
199596,
but law enforcement took no interest in
this case until 2005.
Why was that?
Maria Farmer was the first alleged
victim to come forward and she came
forward in 1996 and she had said that
she went to the New York police and they
directed her to the FBI and she spilled
the beans to the FBI and there was
nothing radio silence. And then in 2005,
this is kind of where the neutron goes
into the plutonium. A 14-year-old girl
told her mother that she had been
molested by Jeffrey Epstein and her
mother and father brought her to the
Palm Beach Police Department. And at
that point, the Palm Beach police just
looked upon Ebstein as a rich
philanthropic type. And but she
described the interior of his home and
also his anatomy. And she was from a a
not a poor background, but a lower
socioeconomic background. And the police
believed her and they quickly found when
they started to investigate other
victims. And by the time they served a
search warrant on Epstein in 2005 and
there were four they had the statements
of four five minors and also 17
corroborating statements. They knew of
23 victims, but they were going to start
with those five. And it was four counts
of unlawful sexual activity with a minor
and one count of loot and lascivious
molestation which could have potentially
landed Ebstein in prison for a very long
time. But then that case was taken away
from them and given to a grand jury and
in Florida generally grand juries are
reser reserved for capital offenses. So,
something was fishy right off the bat.
>> And I don't know if your audience is
familiar with how grand juries work, but
a special prosecutor is chosen to
oversee a grand jury. And grand jurors
are just people that have shown up for
jury duty and been funneled to a grand
jury. And the special prosecutor calls
the witnesses that he or she deems as
important and shows the evidence that he
she deems as important. And there was a
New York Supreme Court judge that said
special prosecutors of grand juries have
so much power over grand juries that
they could get them to indict a ham
sandwich. And that was definitely the
case with the Epstein uh uh grand jury
because
that special prosecutor Lannabell Lovic
only called two victims. One had been 14
when she was molested by Jeffrey Epstein
and she was now 16. And one w was 16
when she'd been molested by Jeffrey
Epstein multiple times and she was uh
now 18. So that grand jury just went by
her lead and she basically skewered both
the uh both the girls and
>> wow
>> was actually calling one a prostitute. I
mean, it I've got I've got I've got the
transcripts. It it was really really
horrible.
>> And that grand jury found that grand
jury was a ham sandwich. It found that
Jeffrey Epstein hadn't molested a single
minor. And the real hero in this story
is Michael Ryder. He was the chief of
the Palm Beach Police Department. He was
threatened. He was followed.
And there was a a terror campaign
against him. But he refused to back
down. And when that grand jury didn't
return any indictments of child abuse
against Jeffrey Epstein, he became quite
viferous and went to the Department of
Justice. And at that time, Alexander
Costa was the US attorney for the
Southern District of Florida. And he
said, "You've got to do something about
this." And Alexander Aosta assured
Writer that he would. And then all of a
sudden there was radio silence.
And what was happening was
team Epstein was negotiating a very very
dirty deal
with the US attorney. And I've got
emails between the assistant US attorney
and Epstein lawyer Jay Leowitz. And the
deal that they've put together is so
dirty
that she says that we got to go to this
magistrate. A magistrate is one step
below a judge in the judiciary and they
can perform the function of judges. She
said we've got to go to this particular
magistrate. He will sign it. So they
went to that particular magistrate and
he signed it. And then the feds sealed
the agreement and lawyers for the
victims at that point and also the Palm
Beach Post appealed the ceiling and Palm
Beach Judge Kenneth Mea decided that
that documentation should be unsealed
and then the feds appealed Mara's ruling
and it was ultimately settled in the
11th Circuit which said unseal it. So,
the 11th Circuit unsealed it and what
was it it was an abomination really. Um,
it gave all of Jeffrey Epstein's
co-conspirators and it named four of
them. It gave all of Jeffrey Epstein's
co-conspirators blanket immunity.
Blanket immunity.
And it circumvented the Victim Crimes
Rights Act, which is a it's a federal
law. And it anytime if you're a victim
in a federal court, the feds have to
apprise you of the adjudication of your
perpetrator and you also get to confront
your perpetrator. But the feds just
trampled on that. So they had the state
make a deal with Ebstein and he got 18
months in county jail. He had to do 13.
But he was let out during the day to
molest little girls. And
Alexander Aosta was being vetted by the
Trump administration and he said why
were why did you give him such a lenient
deal and Acasta said I was told Epstein
was intelligence and I had to back down
and there's I I've talked to various
legal scholars about this there's
there's only
two people in the government that can
tell a US attorney to stand down. one is
the attorney general and one is the
president. Now, Alexander Aosta as a US
attorney isn't going to cover up a
nationwide pedophile network. He's not
going to go out on a limb unless his
superior says cover it up. And Alberto
Gonzalez as the attorney general isn't
going to cover up a nationwide pedophile
network and go out on a limb unless his
superior says cover it up. So ultimately
that cover up lands at the foot of uh
George Bush too.
>> Yeah, I think that's exactly right. You
know, when I was in prison, uh, I was in
a low security prison for 23 months
after blowing the whistle on the CIA's
torture program. Most pedophiles in the
federal prison system are in low
security prisons. They can't go to the
minimum because they'll just walk away
and molest more children. They can't go
to the maximum or the medium because
they're going to be beaten, killed,
shanked, whatever. So, they're all in
the low, almost all in the low. But most
of these guys who committed crimes very
very similar to the crimes that Jeffrey
Epstein committed have sentences of 20
25 30 years
and Epstein got this sweetheart deal. So
I want to ask you about Aosta.
I actually feel a little bit bad for
Aosta because I think that what happened
to him is exactly as you just described.
This was not his decision. He didn't
just wake up one morning and say, "You
know what? I'm going to protect a a
national pedophile ring today." I
believe that he was instructed to do so.
And I also agree with you that it had to
come from the top from George W. Bush. I
have no idea why. But let's talk for a
second about that word intelligence.
That's exactly what Aosta said. He said
that Epstein was intelligence. That
could mean a lot of different things.
That could mean CIA, which doesn't make
much sense to me, but it could mean
Mossad, which makes a lot of sense to
me. I was on the Piers Morgan show a few
weeks ago and I got into a little tiff
with Alan Dersowitz.
He said something and I think he said it
because he was angry because it made no
sense. And when you're a professor of
law at Harvard University Law School,
you shouldn't make silly mistakes like
this. But I said that I believed that uh
that Epstein was an Israeli access
agent. Right? You're not going to if
you're the Israeli Mossad, you're not
going to recruit Bill Clinton. You're
not going to recruit, you know, George
Mitchell or Prince Andrew or whomever.
So, you do the next best thing. You
recruit the person next to those people
who can then report back to you. And in
exchange, you're helping to finance this
lavish lifestyle. So Durowitz exploded
and he said, "I was Jeffrey Epstein's
attorney. If he had been intelligence, I
could have used that to get him a
lighter sentence."
And I said, "A lighter sentence?" I
said, "Professor, with all due respect,
if you had gone to court and said you
should give him a lighter sentence
because he's spying for a foreign
country,
I would have expected to see him hanging
from a tree instead."
So, what do you think? Do you think
we're looking at a foreign intelligence
service? Do you think we're looking at
Mossad? There are these connections that
are well known between Galain Maxwell
and her father and the Israeli Mossad.
Should we just assume the same about
Epstein?
>> Well, with Epstein, he met with William
Burns. Yes. Who would become the head of
the CIA in 2014? I think they met three
times. And why would someone a a career
diplomat who would later be the director
of the CIA? Why would he meet with a And
at that point, Epstein was a convicted
pedophile. So, and we've never gotten a
straight answer about that. When people
ask me about the MSAD, I generally say,
and you've got some expertise in this
area, I generally say that the MSAD very
well might have been working with
Jeffrey Ebstein, but I can't imagine
that the CIA
would not if if if the MSAD was
compromising American politicians on
American soil. I don't think that the
CIA would just be cool with that. I
think that the CIA would want a cut of
that intelligence. And I think the fact
that Bush 2 covered it up is an
indication that it was the CIA. Would
Bush have gone to bat for the MSAD? We
don't know. But he certainly would have
gone to bat for the CIA.
>> See, that's the part that doesn't make
any sense to me. He He probably wouldn't
have gone to bat for Mossad. There there
would have been no reason for him to do
that. But to go to bad for the CIA, of
course, it when you're the president of
the United States and your father was
the director of the CIA before becoming
president of the United States. What I
don't understand, and and this is one of
those questions that really has no
answer unless it's buried deep in some
kind of classified folder. I don't
understand what intelligence
Epstein could have given the CIA that
the CIA didn't already have access to.
That's what I'm conf it confuses me. But
you're right. There are so many
different fingers pointing in the
direction of American intelligence
versus
Israeli or other foreign intelligence.
I spent seven years writing the Franklin
scandal, which is the Epstein scandal is
kind of a carbon copy of the Franklin
scandal. And and those grand juries said
that there were two of them, state and
federal, said that those perpetrators
hadn't molested a single kid. And then
they indicted the kids that wouldn't
recant their accounts of abuse, two of
them. But I I got very deep into it and
I ultimately got in touch with a
blackmail photographer.
And
that's not a job description that
elicits a high degree of ethics.
So,
I was very cautious with what he said
and I do believe I I talked to him at
various times and I do believe initially
he was being pretty honest with me. Um,
I think at a certain point he started to
be dishonest with me and I told him that
and uh haven't talked to him too much
since. But I like his analogy. He's a
unuous guy but he was a smart guy. He
said once you're compromised,
it's like you're on a yacht and it's a
beautiful yacht and it's a beautiful day
and you can have anything you want on
that yacht. But if you decide to get off
the yacht, people are going to make sure
that you drown. The the people on the
yacht are going to make sure that you
drown. And I think that that's the case
with Epstein. But I also think there
might have been blackmail activities. I
mean, he definitely provided girl. I
mean, like George Mitchell, um, I think
he was one of the perpetrators. You
mentioned him. He was the Senate
majority leader. I believe that Epstein
provided an underage girls to George
Mitchell, which is when you look at him,
he looks like a benign grandfatherly.
You would never peg him as as a
pedophile.
But with all the cameras in his homes,
in his New York home, there was a secret
room very much like the Franklin
scandal. And the secret room had
multiple monitors and one of the alleged
victims said that Epstein showed her the
room and that there were men, as in
plural, looking at the monitors. And
then Virginia Gurey said that she had
also seen that room.
So I think that there was also a
blackmail enterprise. I think he was
providing children to the people on the
yacht, but I think that also there was a
potential for blackmail. Also,
I want to ask you about the the black
books because they they've been in the
news a lot lately and much to my
surprise, I get these automated emails
from auction houses all the time. I love
looking at auction cataloges. And so
there's an auction house on the Eastern
Shore of Maryland called Alexander
Auctions. And three or four weeks ago,
they had what they called the Epstein
black book. And it was estimated to sell
for between 80,000 and $120,000
and it it passed. Nobody wanted it. Um,
you actually acquired the black book or
at least a black book that belonged to
to Epstein and it has a very interesting
story behind it. Can you tell us how you
ended up with that black book and why
was it so important?
Alfredo Rodriguez was Jeffrey Epstein's
house manager and he pllined the black
boy and he had been deposed and he was
asked if he had any evidence that contri
that could contribute to the fed's case
and he had said no and then he tried to
sell the black book to one of the
attorneys that was launching civil suits
at uh at Jeffrey Epstein. So the
attorney called the FBI and the FBI did
a sting because Rodriguez had lied about
the black book and he had called the
black book. He wanted $50,000 for it and
he called it the holy grail of Jeffrey
Epstein of the Epstein network. And I
got it in 2012
and it was my first jaunt to Florida.
And I was there for about 3 weeks
knocking on doors talking to people and
um I was able to get it.
And in the black book, Alfredo Rodriguez
circled people that he said were in
cahoots with Jeffrey Epstein as far as
his pedophilic pandering
and and Virginia Gurey and her uh
deposition, sworn deposition, she
corroborated a number of those names. So
with the black book, I initially started
to call victims. There's a bunch of
victims in the black book and I wanted
to know how big this was and most of
them didn't want to talk to me but some
of them did and they were telling me
about being flown around the country and
flown to an island and at that point
Jeffrey Epstein was a lone pedophile.
There wasn't any talk of his collusion
with with other people. soap. I was I
was pretty stunned by that. Um although
it looked eerily similar to Franklin and
but I was still stunned by it. And so I
brought it back to New York City, which
is where I live, the mecca of
publishing, and I tried to sell the
black book in an article on the black
book. And no one wanted to touch it. No
one. And then it took me three years
before a platform rocker was willing to
publish it and and at that point I had
flight logs. I was the first guy to
release the flight logs too. Um and I
wrote some articles on it and and it's
it's kind of strange. I
I just wanted to get it published. I
mean, it it had been rejected by
everyone and I thought, you know,
Gawker, I might as well because it's a
it's a it was a fairly big website. I I
had no idea that it would be like epic
like it turned out to be. And but what's
interesting about that
only two media have acknowledged
that I was the guy that released it.
They they've still stayed away from me.
>> Just crazy. Just crazy.
>> I've got a there's someone who's helping
me now. Uh
He's volunteering his time and he has a
lot of media connections. And I had
dinner with him about two weeks ago and
he said to me, "As a journalist, you're
radioactive."
So,
I just heard yesterday that I'm a I'm a
Russian stoogge. So, welcome to the uh
to the club.
I want to ask you if I could about uh
No, go ahead.
>> I mean, there's a lot of knuckleheads
floating around the internet. You don't
know if they're knuckleheads or they're
actually working for some deep malignant
part of our government. And someone said
that I was a CIA agent and you know, why
would I release the black book and
redact no names?
If I was if I was actually CIA, I would
have been redacting some names. So, I
get a kick out of it.
>> Yeah.
People are not as smart as they want us
to believe they are. I want to ask you
about Galileain Maxwell. I'm utterly
perplexed by this whole situation. She's
at the end of the day, she's the only
person that was convicted of a crime
here besides Epstein. And Epstein, of
course, uh having died in in the MDC
Brooklyn, um
was never, you know, convicted or
sentenced in in the second, uh iteration
of his charges. She she was convicted
and got 20 years. 20 years is a very
long time. She's doing it in a very
comfortable minimum security prison
because if you're a female pedophile,
which is very unusual, you can go to a
minimum security, not if you're a male.
But now, at least this week, she's the
darling of the uh Justice Department.
The president won't rule out pardoning
her. A child sex predator. Pardoning
her. What should we make of all this?
Well, I mean, she really got lucky.
I mean, she the charges she was indicted
on conspiracy to entice minors to travel
and engage in illegal sex acts.
conspiracy to transport minors to
participate in illegal sex acts,
transporting a minor to participate in
illegal sex acts, sex trafficking
conspiracy, and sex trafficking a minor.
That's a heavy sentence in the federal
system. Sex trafficking a minor. That's
15 to life. And and this is I mean this
just shows how screwy this case is. She
was indicted on three conspiracies, but
no one else was indicted.
And
>> so where was the conspiracy?
Unbelievable.
>> What's that?
>> So where was the conspiracy? You can't
be the only person involved in a
conspiracy.
>> And now the feds are saying Jeffrey
Epstein acted alone. So according to the
feds,
you Jeffrey Epste and Golain Maxwell
didn't molest children together, which
definitely isn't true.
>> Which we know is not true.
>> Yeah.
And the Trump administration keeps
getting itself in trouble.
And
on February 7th,
our attorney general, Pam Bondi, or
February 26, she said that she was going
to release all the Epstein files. And
then what she released was really a
nothing sandwich. When I released the
black book, we redacted the adults
numbers and we redacted the victim's
last name and their numbers. And I saw a
rendition of the black book that I put
up that she released to the quote
unquote influencers and every name was
redacted. So,
[Laughter]
she didn't provide us any new
revelations. And then she said that
she'd been bamboozled by the FBI. the
the New York FBI field office. So,
she's telling us that she's going on
national television, she's telling us
that she's going to release
everything and then she says that she's
been bamboozled by the FBI. And
so, either she's lying when she was on
national television, either she was
lying or she's inept. And I'm a
charitable person, so I just said she
was inept. But then she kept on digging
herself into a deeper hole. She declared
that the documents would be released,
but matters of national security would
be redacted. So now she has to tell us
why a bunch of child molesters have
anything to do with national security,
which she didn't. and and the uh the
crescendo of her macity came on May 7th
when she said that there was she said
I'll quote her there are tens of
thousands of videos of Epstein with
children or child porn and there are
hundreds of victims and she said that
they were just going through it at that
point that was but the the FBI couldn't
open Jeffrey Epstein's safe fast enough
the morning after he was arrested the
FBI I opened up and safe and according
to the New York Times, there were lots
of discs with a lot of child abuse
material. And Business Insider reported
that there were there were hard drives.
And you can bet
the FBI and whatever malignant corner of
government that Jeffrey Epstein was
involved in, they were looking at that
stuff that day. They probably did double
shifts because there was a lot of it.
And so for her to say that they're just
now looking at it, that it's been
sitting in a corner of the FBI
collecting dust, that is macity. Just
outright macity.
She seemed to be a little bit
disingenuous, too, when she made that
announcement a couple of weeks ago that
the videos were nothing but child
pornography and they will never see the
light of day. We will never release.
Nobody wants you to release the child
porn videos. We want to know the names
of the individuals who were committing
crimes against children and we want to
know why those people haven't been
charged with a crime. And here we are
weeks later and there's no indication
from the Justice Department that that
information is going to be forthcoming.
I started a nonprofit organization
called Epstein Justice and we want two
simple baseline
acts of decency.
When you cover up a crime, you're aiding
and embedding that crime. So, we want to
know why the government has aid and
embedded child trafficking in the
Epstein case. And we want the
perpetrators to be prosecuted.
And it's it's very simple. And that's
what we're we've been gearing up for it.
And uh that's what we really want is an
independent congressional investigation.
But we can get a bead on some of the
perpetrators. We can get double
corroboration. Like Rodriguez
circled
people that he said were in cahoots with
Jeffrey Epstein and his pedophilic
pandering. And Gla Maxwell has circled
who was obviously in cahoots. and
Virginia Guffrey named her as a
perpetrator.
Former Israeli Prime Minister Aud Barack
is circled and Virginia Guffrey named
him as a perpetrator. The billionaire
Les Wexner is circled and he had a very
close relationship with Epstein. Um
Virginia Gruff said that he was a per
same thing with Alan Dersowitz. Durowitz
is circled and Guffrey said that he's a
perpetrator. And Bill Richardson, the
former New Mexico governor and also
Clint Zar Gizar is circled and goofy
said that she had been molested by him.
She waffled a little bit with Alan
Dersowitz and I don't know why I I think
that she had she was leveraged. I think
that there was some stuff in her family
that made her susceptible to leverage.
At least that's my I I knew Virginia and
um I was really stunned when she waffled
a little bit on Durowitz and I called
one of her attorneys who I've become
buddies with and uh he said, "Man, I
can't I can't talk about it. I'm really
sorry." So, something happened there
that we don't know and hopefully we will
at some point know what what went on
there.
I wanted to ask you too just in the last
couple of days there um have been
reports that that
Galain Maxwell at least Galain Maxwell's
attorneys may be negotiating some sort
of an agreement with with leaders on
Capitol Hill that would allow her to
testify under a grant of immunity.
Immunity from what are there other
uncharged crimes that she may be
associated with?
She Golain Maxwell helped Ebstein
traffic girls for 20 to 25 years. And as
I said, if you wanted to indict her on
child trafficking, I mean, I don't know,
20 times, 30 times, 40 times, 50 times.
There was that strange document that was
released by the Department of Justice
and the FBI that no one signed. It was
released on July 6th and no one signed
it. No one's going to take the fall for
that document. There's a couple of
things I do agree with that there was
300 gigabytes of material that was taken
from that was impounded from Epstein.
And I also agree that there were over a
thousand victims and there were
definitely over a thousand victims I
believe. But then the that report kind
of jumps the tracks of reality. It says
that Jeffrey Epstein acted alone
and and that there wasn't any blackmail
involved. So to say that Jeffrey Epstein
acted alone is really egregious because
I've been I've been writing and
researching about child trafficking for
over two decades now. And I' I've spoke
like the national serial exploitation
has a world summit every year and I've
spoken at three of those. I've spoken at
a lot of conferences and um and and
actually I've written
on child trafficking for people that
that deal with uh dissociative identity
disorder. I contributed a chapter to it.
So I've gotten to know um victims of
these crimes pretty well over the years.
And the best thing you can say to a
victim of child sexual abuse or of
sexual assault is, "I believe you."
That's by far the best thing that you
can say. The worst thing you can say is,
"I don't believe you." And so the
Department of Justice and the FBI are
saying that they don't believe hundreds
of girls. And that's that's that's
abhorrent to me.
It certainly is.
Uh figures are beginning to point this
week at uh at Donald Trump for a number
of reasons. First of all, this statement
that just seems utterly counterintuitive
that there are no files.
You know, maybe there's not a file that
says list of Jeffrey Epstein's
sex co-conspirators. Sure. Okay, I'll
concede that maybe that file doesn't
exist, but come on. Are are we
are we in a situation here where to
paraphrase uh uh Bill Clinton, it
depends on what the meaning of file is?
What are there files? Right. There have
to be files. What are we talking about
here?
I mean there people were talking about
an Epstein list and it's not like
Jeffrey Ebstein ran a travel agency and
he kept a list of his clients
>> on on his refrigerator with a magnet. I
mean but the black book names a lot of
perpetrators. A lot of them are circled
but a lot of them aren't. You can, one
of the things that kind of differentiate
a perpetrator from a non-perpetrator in
the black book is the number of contacts
that Epstein had for them. With Clinton,
I think he had 24 contacts and with
Trump, I think he had about 12. The
Trump administration is really hurting
itself. It came out with that 76
document that said Jeffrey Epstein act
alone and then Donald Trump was blaming
it on the Democrats that it was a
Democrat conspiracy.
But the the the the coverup started
under Bush 2. So it wasn't a Democratic
conspiracy. If you want to call it a
conspiracy, it was it was a Republican
conspiracy. And I'm not a Republican or
a Democrat. I have no dog in that fight.
I'm I'm just looking for the truth.
Neither do I.
>> Mhm.
>> So
with Donald Trump saying that it was a
Democrat, I mean, he's like Pam Bondi
and Patel, they just keep digging
themselves in a deeper and deeper and
deeper hole. And when uh Speaker of the
House Mike Johnson came out and said
that he was adjourning Congress early so
it couldn't vote on Representative
Massiey's bill to investigate Jeffrey
Epstein's child trafficking. That's kind
of mind-boggling to me. And Mike Johnson
constitutionally is the third more most
powerful man in the country. and for him
to shut down Congress
so it couldn't vote on a bill to
investigate a child trafficking network.
I mean that's it's that that's evil. I
mean it's nefarious. It's and slightly
surreal too. and and I he is
I've been reading articles about him and
he has this software on his phone called
Covenant Eye and his 17-year-old also
has the same software on his phone and
they monitor each other's
use of pornography.
So, he's monitoring his son's use of
pornography who was 17 and the
17-year-old son is monitoring his use of
pornography. And I'll say this, and you
know how sophisticated
the the intelligence agency intelligence
agencies are with uh with their cyber
abilities. Um,
if Johnson is looking at certain types
of pornography
or child abuse material, it wouldn't be
hard to tell him, you've got to shut
down Congress. And that's certainly
within the realm of reason in this
story.
You know what? I I hadn't considered
that, but that's a very good point. That
certainly could be it. But that then
leads to the next question. You've gone
through this with a fine tooth comb over
the course of years. Is there anything
that you've seen that would lead you to
believe that Donald Trump has something
to worry about personally?
Okay. Donald Trump's name is circled in
the black book
and he was dishonest about he said he
hadn't been to Epstein's home. He had
been to Epstein's home. Um, and he was
also on Epstein's Jet. There was someone
named Katie Johnson who filed a lawsuit
against Trump and Maxwell and that was
her pseudonym. And she said that she'd
been molested by both Trump and Maxwell.
And there was an accompanying affidavit,
too.
And then she retracted her lawsuit. And
I've heard multiple stories on why she
might have retracted her lawsuit. We
just don't know. But I looked for her
and looked for her and looked for her
for three years and I found her.
>> Wow.
>> And because she she might be a victim, I
decided that I wasn't
>> Well, here's the thing. I I decided not
to call her. I decided not to text her.
I emailed her and she's never got back.
And this was over the course of the last
three and a half years, I've emailed her
four times and she's never gotten back
to me. And I see that she's put together
a life for herself. She's selling real
estate in the Southwest. She's got a
boyfriend. They go to Europe
occasionally. So, it's difficult to know
what went on there. I would I would love
for her to talk to me and then I would I
would I could get a beat on whether or
not I felt she was telling the truth. So
Katie Johnson is the only victim that we
know of underage victim to accuse Donald
Trump. But then that's such a convoluted
ambiguous tale that it's it's really
difficult to know what the truth is with
with Katie Johnson.
Justice for the the victims aside, I
want to talk about the punishment side.
Jeffrey Epstein's dead. Galileain
Maxwell is serving a 20-year prison
sentence, at least for the time being.
Are there others who are at risk of
being prosecuted at this point?
Absolutely. We know the names of a bunch
of pimps and the New York Times did a
page article on on six pimps. Glenn
Maxwell was of course the leading pimp
but there is Sarah Kellen, Leslie Grath,
Adriana Ross and Nadia Marson Kova and
they knew all about that operation. They
they knew everything about it. all the
nuances, all the pers, and just with the
information in that New York Times
article, they could be indicted.
And they could be indicted on multiple
counts of child trafficking.
>> And if you indicted Kellen Gr and
they're they've been taken care of very
well. Uh, Kellen, I think, has a $4
million house in Manhattan and a $3
million house um I believe North
Carolina, but but don't quote me, but
Kellen Grath Ross and Marson Kova could
be indicted on multiple counts of child
trafficking. And if if our Department of
Justice was actually going to prosecute
this case, it would be like kind of like
a RICO case where you would indict them
on multiple counts of child trafficking,
which is, as I said, a heavy sentence,
15 years to life, and then they would
roll over on the per.
And then we've got lots of victims that
would if if they could feel safe,
I think that they would come forward if
they they could feel safe. There was the
Epstein victim's compensation program
and there were 225
women and young women that applied for
it and 150 were given settlement or 138
were given settlements. 12 declined
because and this is nefarious too. If
you took any money at all from that the
Epstein victim's compensated program,
you had to sign an NDA
and you couldn't go after any of your
other perpetrators, which is another
indication that Jeffrey Epstein didn't
act alone. But and we don't even know
the criteria
for what goes on in that program because
a number of women have been rejected who
are definitely pandered by Jeffrey
Epstein and and molested by Jeffrey
Epstein. And this is kind of ominous.
The media has just been horrible in in
in this case. I mean, no one they're
good at digging up salacious dirt, but
no one in the media has really called
for justice. I'm not aware of a major
media outlet that that that's called for
justice,
but the the media has settled that the
youngest Epstein victim was 14 years
old. And I know two therapists. One's a
pretty eminent psychologist. And she's
has a client who she believes was
trafficked by Jeffrey Epstein when she
was under 10 years old. And I know
another therapist who has a client and
she believes that her client was
trafficked by Jeffrey Epstein when she
was under 10 years old. And actually the
first victim describes the interior of
his house, his New York house. And both
those therapists feel that their clients
weren't given settlements because they
didn't fit the cover story of 14 years
or older. And and that's really honest.
with the Franklin network
that the same thing happened. I mean,
those pimps were into pubescent boys,
but if you wanted a seven-year-old or an
8-year-old, they they had no compunction
about that. They I mean, these guys are
psychopaths.
>> And Epste was buying Epste
>> Epste was buying children in Eastern
Europe, which is mindboggling to me,
too. I I want you I'm going to pull it
up. I want you if you could uh to tell
us about um a variety of of um websites.
We've got uh really the most important
one is Nick Bryantnenyc.com.
Uh you've you've really stacked this
with great articles and interviews. You
have a blog. Your your many books are
listed. I I I didn't have time to
mention um all of the books. It's quite
impressive. one, two, three, four, five
so far. Um, but tell us where people can
go to learn more. You've got Facebook,
you've got X, you have a number of
different outlets. Tell us about that.
>> The most important thing, the most
important website that people should go
to is epste.com.
We're taking on the Congress and we
we're and we're getting bigger and
bigger and bigger and we need a majority
in the House and a Senate to form an
independent congressional commission.
That would include citizen citizens like
me, people that really wanted to do the
right thing. If this thing goes into a
subcommittee, it's I mean it's going to
die. So
>> it it'll never see the light of day.
>> Yeah.
So, we need an independent congressional
and
um Thomas Massie has said that he will
endorse this. So, that's great. And then
he's put out that bill uh 581 and
there's 34 legislators that will that
that are co-sponsoring that bill. So,
we're going to start calling them at
this point. And um what we need is to
get momentum
and make sure this doesn't we can shame
these legislators
into voting into doing the right thing.
As soon as Mike Johnson made that macob
announcement, we made made him the
legislator of the week. We have the
legislator of the week where we put up
and we have people call and call his
office or his various offices. So the
the week before Mike Thompson was the
legislator of the week and if I mean
people think that they don't have any
power and that it's impenetrable, but if
a legislator gets 20 to 30 phone calls
about an issue, they're they're going to
notice that for sure without any doubt.
Well, I could talk to you for hours.
We're going to leave it there. Nick
Bryant,
thank you so much for joining us. Uh we
we would love to stay in touch. This
this thing is continuing to develop.
It's like something new pops up every
day or two. So, thank you so much for
joining us. And ladies and gentlemen, I
wanted to ask you again, just like I did
in the last interview and the and the
one before, please please hit the hit
the subscribe and like buttons. It
doesn't cost a scent and you can't even
imagine how much that helps us. So, we
really appreciate it, Nick. Thanks again
for being on Deep Focus. We'll see you
next time.
>> Okay, John. Thanks.
>> Bye-bye.